How many languages do you speak?
你会说多少种语言？
For most people, it can be hard learning just one foreign language.
对大多数人来说，仅仅学习一门外语就够难的了。
Lydia Machova, a Slovakian polyglot and language mentor, is currently fluent in seven foreign languages and says she likes to learn a new language every two years!
斯洛伐克籍多语者、语言导师莉迪亚·马乔娃目前能流利地说七门外语，并表示她喜欢每两年学习一门新语言！
So how do polyglots like Lydia learn multiple languages successfully, and what can we learn from their methods?
那么，像莉迪亚这样的多语者是如何成功学习多种语言的？我们能从他们的方法中学到什么呢？
Lydia wanted to find out the different techniques polyglots use, and she found a wide variety of methods.
莉迪亚想了解多语者使用的不同技巧，她发现了各种各样的方法。
Some use language exchange apps to find native speakers so that they can start speaking from day one.
有些人使用语言交换应用程序寻找母语者，以便从第一天就开始开口说。
Others watch series they love with subtitles, and some use techniques like 'shadowing' – listening to and repeating target language to master pronunciation.
另一些人则观看他们喜爱的带字幕的剧集，还有一些人使用诸如"影子跟读"之类的技巧——通过听和重复目标语言来掌握发音。
Kato Lomb was described by the linguist Krashen as "possibly the most accomplished polyglot in the world".
语言学家克拉申将卡托·隆布描述为"可能是世界上最杰出的多语者"。
She was a Hungarian who spoke 16 languages!
她是匈牙利人，会说16种语言！
Her approach to learning focussed on extensive reading and self-study.
她的学习方法侧重于广泛阅读和自学。
So, while there are lots of different approaches, in her 2019 TED Talk, Lydia concluded that the one thing polyglots all have in common is an interest and motivation to learn.
因此，尽管有很多不同的方法，莉迪亚在2019年的TED演讲中总结道，多语者都有一个共同点，那就是对学习的兴趣和动力。
However, some linguists argue that viral videos showing polyglots switching between languages often rely on memorised phrases rather than proving genuine conversational ability.
然而，一些语言学家认为，展示多语者在不同语言间切换的爆火视频往往依赖于背诵的短语，并不能证明真实的会话能力。
Benny Lewis, author and creator of the website Fluent in 3 Months, thinks it's important to be open and honest about your competency in a language.
网站"三个月流利"的作者兼创始人本尼·刘易斯认为，对自己的语言能力保持坦诚和诚实很重要。
He discusses having varying levels of proficiency in the languages he speaks, from basic conversation to near-native fluency.
他谈到自己所讲的语言有不同水平，从基础会话到接近母语的流利度。
So, the professionals say enjoy yourself when learning.
所以，专业人士说，学习时要享受过程。
We recommend you try some of these suggestions, find the right method for you and stick to it!
我们建议你尝试这些建议中的一些，找到适合你的方法，并坚持下去！